{
    "Maths": [
        {
            "question_number": 1,
            "question": "The distance of the line (x-2)/2 = (y-6)/3 = (z-3)/4 from the point (1,4,0) along the line x/1 = (y-2)/2 = (z+3)/3 is:",
            "options": [
                "√17",
                "√15",
                "√14",
                "√13"
            ],
            "answer": "√14"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 2,
            "question": "Let A = {(x,y) ∈ R×R : |x+y| ≥ 3} and B = {(x,y) ∈ R×R : |x|+|y| ≤ 3}. If C = {(x,y) ∈ A ∩ B : x=0 or y=0}, then ∑_{(x,y)∈C} |x+y| is:",
            "options": [
                "15",
                "24",
                "18",
                "12"
            ],
            "answer": "12"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 3,
            "question": "Let X = R × R. Define a relation R on X as: (a1,b1) R (a2,b2) iff b1 = b2. Statement I: R is an equivalence relation. Statement II: For some (a,b) in X, the set S = {(x,y) in X: (x,y) R (a,b)} represents a line parallel to y=x. In the light of the above statements, choose the correct answer:",
            "options": [
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are false",
                "Statement I is true but Statement II is false",
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are true",
                "Statement I is false but Statement II is true"
            ],
            "answer": "Statement I is true but Statement II is false"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 4,
            "question": "Let ∫x³sinx dx = g(x) + C, where C is the constant of integration. If 8(g(π/2) + g'(π/2)) = απ³ + βπ² + γ, α,β,γ ∈ Z, then α + β - γ equals:",
            "options": [
                "48",
                "55",
                "62",
                "47"
            ],
            "answer": "55"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 5,
            "question": "A rod of length eight units moves such that its ends A and B always lie on the lines x-y+2=0 and y+2=0, respectively. If the locus of the point P, that divides the rod AB internally in the ratio 2:1 is 9(x²+αy²+βxy+γx+28y)-76=0, then α-β-γ is equal to:",
            "options": [
                "22",
                "21",
                "23",
                "24"
            ],
            "answer": "23"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 6,
            "question": "If the square of the shortest distance between the lines (x-2)/1 = (y-1)/2 = (z+3)/-3 and (x+1)/2 = (y+3)/4 = (z+5)/-5 is m/n, where m, n are coprime numbers, then m+n is equal to:",
            "options": [
                "21",
                "9",
                "14",
                "6"
            ],
            "answer": "9"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 7,
            "question": "lim_{x→∞} [(2x²-3x+5)(3x-1)^{x/2}] / [(3x²+5x+4)√((3x+2)^x)] is equal to:",
            "options": [
                "2/√3e",
                "2e/√3",
                "2/(3√e)",
                "2e/3"
            ],
            "answer": "2/(3√e)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 8,
            "question": "Let the point A divide the line segment joining the points P(-1,-1,2) and Q(5,5,10) internally in the ratio r:1 (r>0). If O is the origin and (OQ·OA) - (1/5)|OP×OA|² = 10, then the value of r is:",
            "options": [
                "√7",
                "14",
                "3",
                "7"
            ],
            "answer": "7"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 9,
            "question": "The length of the chord of the ellipse x²/4 + y²/2 = 1, whose mid-point is (1, 1/2), is:",
            "options": [
                "5/3√15",
                "1/3√15",
                "2/3√15",
                "√15"
            ],
            "answer": "2/3√15"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 10,
            "question": "The system of equations x+y+z=6, x+2y+5z=9 has no solution if x+5y+λz=μ, then:",
            "options": [
                "λ=15, μ≠17",
                "λ≠17, μ≠18",
                "λ=17, μ≠18",
                "λ=17, μ=18"
            ],
            "answer": "λ=17, μ≠18"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 11,
            "question": "Let the range of the function f(x)=6+16cosx·cos(π/3−x)·cos(π/3+x)·sin3x·cos6x, x∈R be [α,β]. Then the distance of the point (α,β) from the line 3x+4y+12=0 is:",
            "options": [
                "11",
                "8",
                "10",
                "9"
            ],
            "answer": "11"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 12,
            "question": "Let x=x(y) be the solution of the differential equation y=(x−y dx/dy)sin(x/y), y>0 and x(1)=π/2. Then cos(x(2)) is equal to:",
            "options": [
                "1-2(ln2)²",
                "1-2ln2",
                "2ln2-1",
                "2(ln2)²-1"
            ],
            "answer": "2(ln2)²-1"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 13,
            "question": "A spherical chocolate ball has a layer of ice-cream of uniform thickness around it. When the thickness of the ice-cream layer is 1 cm, the ice-cream melts at the rate of 81 cm³/min and the thickness of the ice-cream layer decreases at the rate of 1/(4π) cm/min. The surface area (in cm²) of the chocolate ball (without the ice-cream layer) is:",
            "options": [
                "196π",
                "256π",
                "225π",
                "128π"
            ],
            "answer": "256π"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 14,
            "question": "The number of complex numbers z, satisfying |z|=1 and |z/z̄ + z̄/z|=1, is:",
            "options": [
                "4",
                "8",
                "10",
                "6"
            ],
            "answer": "8"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 15,
            "question": "Let A=[a_{ij}] be a 3×3 matrix such that A[0;1;0]=[0;0;1], A[4;1;3]=[0;1;0] and A[2;1;2]=[1;0;0], then a_{23} equals:",
            "options": [
                "-1",
                "2",
                "1",
                "0"
            ],
            "answer": "-1"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 16,
            "question": "If I=∫₀^{π/2} [sin^{3/2}x / (sin^{3/2}x + cos^{3/2}x)] dx, then ∫₀^{21} [x sinx cosx / (sin⁴x + cos⁴x)] dx equals:",
            "options": [
                "π²/12",
                "π²/4",
                "π²/16",
                "π²/8"
            ],
            "answer": "π²/16"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 17,
            "question": "A board has 16 squares as shown in the figure. Out of these 16 squares, two squares are chosen at random. The probability that they have no side in common is:",
            "options": [
                "7/10",
                "4/5",
                "23/30",
                "3/5"
            ],
            "answer": "4/5"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 18,
            "question": "Let the shortest distance from (a,0), a>0, to the parabola y²=4x be 4. Then the equation of the circle passing through the point (a,0) and the focus of the parabola, and having its centre on the axis of the parabola is:",
            "options": [
                "x²+y²-10x+9=0",
                "x²+y²-6x+5=0",
                "x²+y²-4x+3=0",
                "x²+y²-8x+7=0"
            ],
            "answer": "x²+y²-6x+5=0"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 19,
            "question": "If in the expansion of (1+x)^p (1-x)^q, the coefficients of x and x² are 1 and -2, respectively, then p²+q² is equal to:",
            "options": [
                "18",
                "13",
                "8",
                "20"
            ],
            "answer": "13"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 20,
            "question": "If the area of the region {(x,y): -1≤x≤1, 0≤y≤a+e^{|x|}-e^{-x}, a>0} is (e²+8e+1)/e, then the value of a is:",
            "options": [
                "8",
                "7",
                "5",
                "6"
            ],
            "answer": "5"
        }
    ],
    "Physics": [
        {
            "question_number": 26,
            "question": "A galvanometer having a coil of resistance 30Ω needs 20 mA of current for full-scale deflection. If a maximum current of 3A is to be measured using this galvanometer, the resistance of the shunt to be added to the galvanometer should be 30/X Ω, where X is",
            "options": [
                "596",
                "149",
                "298",
                "447"
            ],
            "answer": "149"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 27,
            "question": "A ball having kinetic energy KE, is projected at an angle of 60° from the horizontal. What will be the kinetic energy of ball at the highest point of its flight?",
            "options": [
                "KE/8",
                "KE/2",
                "KE/16",
                "KE/4"
            ],
            "answer": "KE/4"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 28,
            "question": "Two charges 7μC and -4μC are placed at (-7cm,0,0) and (7cm,0,0) respectively. Given, ε₀=8.85×10^{-12} C²N^{-1}m^{-2}, the electrostatic potential energy of the charge configuration is:",
            "options": [
                "-1.8 J",
                "-2.0 J",
                "-1.5 J",
                "-1.2 J"
            ],
            "answer": "-1.8 J"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 29,
            "question": "Two point charges -4μC and 4μC, constituting an electric dipole, are placed at (-9,0,0) cm and (9,0,0) cm in a uniform electric field of strength 10⁴ N/C. The work done on the dipole in rotating it from the equilibrium through 180° is:",
            "options": [
                "18.4 mJ",
                "14.4 mJ",
                "12.4 mJ",
                "16.4 mJ"
            ],
            "answer": "14.4 mJ"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 30,
            "question": "A massless spring gets elongated by amount x₁ under a tension of 5 N. Its elongation is x₂ under the tension of 7 N. For the elongation of (5x₁-2x₂), the tension in the spring will be:",
            "options": [
                "39 N",
                "15 N",
                "11 N",
                "20 N"
            ],
            "answer": "11 N"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 31,
            "question": "Water of mass m gram is slowly heated to increase the temperature from T₁ to T₂. The change in entropy of the water, given specific heat of water is 1 Jkg⁻¹K⁻¹, is:",
            "options": [
                "m ln(T₂/T₁)",
                "zero",
                "m ln(T₁/T₂)",
                "m(T₂-T₁)"
            ],
            "answer": "m ln(T₂/T₁)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 32,
            "question": "Water flows in a horizontal pipe whose one end is closed with a valve. The reading of the pressure gauge attached to the pipe is P₁. The reading of the pressure gauge falls to P₂ when the valve is opened. The speed of water flowing in the pipe is proportional to",
            "options": [
                "P₁-P₂",
                "(P₁-P₂)^4",
                "(P₁-P₂)^2",
                "√(P₁-P₂)"
            ],
            "answer": "√(P₁-P₂)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 33,
            "question": "A concave mirror of focal length f in air is dipped in a liquid of refractive index μ. Its focal length in the liquid will be:",
            "options": [
                "μf",
                "f",
                "f/(μ-1)",
                "f/μ"
            ],
            "answer": "f"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 34,
            "question": "What is the current through the battery in the circuit shown below?",
            "options": [
                "1.5 A",
                "0.5 A",
                "0.25 A",
                "1.0 A"
            ],
            "answer": "0.5 A"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 35,
            "question": "The refractive index of the material of a glass prism is √3. The angle of minimum deviation is equal to the angle of the prism. What is the angle of the prism?",
            "options": [
                "60°",
                "58°",
                "48°",
                "50°"
            ],
            "answer": "60°"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 36,
            "question": "The width of one of the two slits in Young's double slit experiment is d while that of the other slit is xd. If the ratio of the maximum to the minimum intensity in the interference pattern on the screen is 9:4 then what is the value of x?",
            "options": [
                "4",
                "5",
                "3",
                "2"
            ],
            "answer": "2"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 37,
            "question": "Using the given P-V diagram, the work done by an ideal gas along the path ABCD is:",
            "options": [
                "3P₀V₀",
                "-4P₀V₀",
                "-3P₀V₀",
                "4P₀V₀"
            ],
            "answer": "-3P₀V₀"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 38,
            "question": "A plane electromagnetic wave of frequency 20 MHz travels in free space along the +x direction. At a particular point in space and time, the electric field vector of the wave is E_y=9.3 V/m. Then, the magnetic field vector of the wave at that point is",
            "options": [
                "B_z=6.2×10^{-8} T",
                "B_z=3.1×10^{-8} T",
                "B_z=1.55×10^{-8} T",
                "B_z=9.3×10^{-8} T"
            ],
            "answer": "3.1×10^{-8} T"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 39,
            "question": "The equation of a transverse wave travelling along a string is y(x,t)=4.0 sin[20×10^{-3}x+600t] mm, where x is in mm and t is in second. The velocity of the wave is:",
            "options": [
                "-60 m/s",
                "+30 m/s",
                "+60 m/s",
                "-30 m/s"
            ],
            "answer": "-30 m/s"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 40,
            "question": "Assertion (A): The binding energy per nucleon is found to be practically independent of the atomic number A, for nuclei with mass numbers between 30 and 170. Reason (R): Nuclear force is long range. In the light of the above statements, choose the correct answer:",
            "options": [
                "(A) is true but (R) is false",
                "(A) is false but (R) is true",
                "Both (A) and (R) are true and (R) is the correct explanation of (A)",
                "Both (A) and (R) are true but (R) is NOT the correct explanation of (A)"
            ],
            "answer": "(A) is true but (R) is false"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 41,
            "question": "If a satellite orbiting the Earth is 9 times closer to the Earth than the Moon, what is the time period of rotation of the satellite? Given rotational time period of Moon =27 days and gravitational attraction between the satellite and the moon is neglected.",
            "options": [
                "27 days",
                "1 day",
                "81 days",
                "3 days"
            ],
            "answer": "1 day"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 42,
            "question": "A circular disk of radius R meter and mass M kg is rotating around the axis perpendicular to the disk. An external torque is applied to the disk such that θ(t)=5t²−8t, where θ(t) is the angular position of the rotating disc as a function of time t. How much power is delivered by the applied torque, when t=2 s?",
            "options": [
                "72MR²",
                "8MR²",
                "108MR²",
                "60MR²"
            ],
            "answer": "60MR²"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 43,
            "question": "The energy of a system is given as E(t)=α³e^{-βt}, where t is the time and β=0.3 s^{-1}. The errors in the measurement of α and t are 1.2% and 1.6%, respectively. At t=5 s, maximum percentage error in the energy is:",
            "options": [
                "6%",
                "8.4%",
                "11.6%",
                "4%"
            ],
            "answer": "6%"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 44,
            "question": "Match List - I with List - II. (A) Permeability of free space (B) Magnetic field (C) Magnetic moment (D) Torsional constant. (I) [ML²T^{-2}] (II) [MT^{-2}A^{-1}] (III) [MLT^{-2}A^{-2}] (IV) [L²A].",
            "options": [
                "(A)-(IV), (B)-(III), (C)-(I), (D)-(II)",
                "(A)-(III), (B)-(II), (C)-(IV), (D)-(I)",
                "(A)-(I), (B)-(IV), (C)-(II), (D)-(III)",
                "(A)-(II), (B)-(I), (C)-(III), (D)-(IV)"
            ],
            "answer": "(A)-(III), (B)-(II), (C)-(IV), (D)-(I)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 45,
            "question": "In photoelectric effect an em-wave is incident on a metal surface and electrons are ejected from the surface. If the work function of the metal is 2.14 eV and stopping potential is 2 V, what is the wavelength of the emwave? (Given hc=1242 eV·nm where h is Planck's constant and c is the speed of light in vacuum.)",
            "options": [
                "300 nm",
                "400 nm",
                "600 nm",
                "200 nm"
            ],
            "answer": "300 nm"
        }
    ],
    "Chemistry": [
        {
            "question_number": 51,
            "question": "Identify the products [A] and [B], respectively in the following reaction: (ii) H⁺ (i) NaOH, 623 K, 300 atm [A] →[H₂SO₄/Na₂Cr₂O₇][B]",
            "options": [
                "C₆H₆, C₆H₅OH",
                "C₆H₅OH, O=C1C=CC(=O)C=C1",
                "C₆H₅OH, [NH₂⁺]OC₆H₅",
                "C₆H₆, O=C1C=CC=CC1"
            ],
            "answer": "C₆H₅OH, O=C1C=CC(=O)C=C1"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 52,
            "question": "Consider the following reactions K₂Cr₂O₇ →[KOH/-H₂O][A] →[H₂SO₄/-H₂O][B]+K₂SO₄. The products [A] and [B], respectively are:",
            "options": [
                "K₂CrO₄ and CrO",
                "K₂CrO₄ and Cr₂O₃",
                "K₂CrO₄ and K₂Cr₂O₇",
                "K₂Cr(OH)₆ and Cr₂O₃"
            ],
            "answer": "K₂CrO₄ and K₂Cr₂O₇"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 53,
            "question": "The effect of temperature on spontaneity of reactions are represented as: (A) ΔH=+, ΔS=-, any T: Non spontaneous (B) ΔH=+, ΔS=+, low T: Non spontaneous (C) ΔH=-, ΔS=-, low T: spontaneous (D) ΔH=-, ΔS=+, any T: spontaneous. Choose the correct answer:",
            "options": [
                "(B) and (C) only",
                "(B) and (D) only",
                "(A) and (D) only",
                "(A) and (C) only"
            ],
            "answer": "(B) and (D) only"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 54,
            "question": "Which of the following graphs most appropriately represents a zero order reaction?",
            "options": [
                "(1)",
                "(2)",
                "(3)",
                "(4)"
            ],
            "answer": "(1)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 55,
            "question": "Consider the reaction X₂Y(g) = X₂(g) + ½Y₂(g). The equation representing correct relationship between the degree of dissociation (x) of X₂Y(g) with its equilibrium constant Kp is ___. Assume x to be very very small.",
            "options": [
                "x=∛[2Kp/p]",
                "x=∛[2Kp²/p]",
                "x=∛[Kp/p]",
                "x=∛[Kp/2p]"
            ],
            "answer": "x=∛[2Kp²/p]"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 56,
            "question": "Given below are two statements: Consider the following reaction R + H₂O → K O C_R^OH. Statement (I): In the case of formaldehyde, K is about 2280, due to small substituents, hydration is faster. Statement (II): In the case of trichloro, K is about 2000 due to -I effect of -Cl. In the light of the above statements, choose the correct answer:",
            "options": [
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are false",
                "Statement I is true but Statement II is false",
                "Statement I is false but Statement II is true",
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are true"
            ],
            "answer": "Both Statement I and Statement II are true"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 57,
            "question": "Given below are two statements: Statement (I): For a given shell, the total number of allowed orbitals is given by n². Statement (II): For any subshell, the spatial orientation of the orbitals is given by -l to +l values including zero. In the light of the above statements, choose the correct answer:",
            "options": [
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are false",
                "Statement I is true but Statement II is false",
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are true",
                "Statement I is false but Statement II is true"
            ],
            "answer": "Both Statement I and Statement II are true"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 58,
            "question": "Standard electrode potentials for a few half cells are mentioned below: E_{Cu²⁺/Cu}°=0.34 V, E_{Zn²⁺/Zn}°=-0.76 V, E_{Ag⁺/Ag}°=0.80 V, E_{Mg²⁺/Mg}°=-2.37 V. Which one of the following cells gives the most negative value of ΔG°?",
            "options": [
                "Zn|Zn²⁺(1M)||Ag⁺(1M)|Ag",
                "Zn|Zn²⁺(1M)||Mg²⁺(1M)|Mg",
                "Ag|Ag⁺(1M)||Mg²⁺(1M)|Mg",
                "Cu|Cu²⁺(1M)||Ag⁺(1M)|Ag"
            ],
            "answer": "Zn|Zn²⁺(1M)||Ag⁺(1M)|Ag"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 59,
            "question": "The α-Helix and β-Pleated sheet structures of protein are associated with its:",
            "options": [
                "tertiary structure",
                "quaternary structure",
                "secondary structure",
                "primary structure"
            ],
            "answer": "secondary structure"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 60,
            "question": "Given below are the atomic numbers of some group 14 elements. The atomic number of the element with lowest melting point is:",
            "options": [
                "6",
                "82",
                "14",
                "50"
            ],
            "answer": "50"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 61,
            "question": "Given below are two statements about X-ray spectra of elements: Statement (I): A plot of √v (v= frequency of X-rays emitted) vs atomic mass is a straight line. Statement (II): A plot of v(v= frequency of X-rays emitted) vs atomic number is a straight line. In the light of the above statements, choose the correct answer:",
            "options": [
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are true",
                "Statement I is false but Statement II is true",
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are false",
                "Statement I is true but Statement II is false"
            ],
            "answer": "Both Statement I and Statement II are false"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 62,
            "question": "Identify A, B and C in the given below reaction sequence: A →[HNO₃] Pb(NO₃)₂ →[H₂SO₄] B →[1) Ammonium (2) Acetic acid (3) K₂CrO₄] C",
            "options": [
                "PbCl₂, PbSO₄, PbCrO₄",
                "PbS, PbSO₄, Pb(CH₃COO)₂",
                "PbCl₂, Pb(SO₄)₂, PbCrO₄",
                "PbS, PbSO₄, PbCrO₄"
            ],
            "answer": "PbS, PbSO₄, PbCrO₄"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 63,
            "question": "Given below are two statements: Statement (I): The boiling points of alcohols and phenols increase with increase in the number of C-atoms. Statement (II): The boiling points of alcohols and phenols are higher in comparison to other class of compounds such as ethers, haloalkanes. In the light of the above statements, choose the correct answer:",
            "options": [
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are false",
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are true",
                "Statement I is false but Statement II is true",
                "Statement I is true but Statement II is false"
            ],
            "answer": "Both Statement I and Statement II are true"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 64,
            "question": "Consider a binary solution of two volatile liquid components 1 and 2. x₁ and y₁ are the mole fractions of component 1 in liquid and vapour phase, respectively. The slope and intercept of the linear plot of 1/x₁ vs 1/y₁ are given respectively as:",
            "options": [
                "P₂⁰/P₁⁰, (P₂⁰-P₁⁰)/P₂⁰",
                "P₁⁰/P₂⁰, (P₂⁰-P₁⁰)/P₂⁰",
                "P₁⁰/P₂⁰, (P₁⁰-P₂⁰)/P₂⁰",
                "P₂⁰/P₁⁰, (P₁⁰-P₂⁰)/P₂⁰"
            ],
            "answer": "P₁⁰/P₂⁰, (P₂⁰-P₁⁰)/P₂⁰"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 65,
            "question": "The ascending order of relative rate of solvolysis of following compounds is: (A) CC1(C)CCC(C)(Br)CC1 (B) O=C1CCC(Br)c2ccccc21 (C) BrC(c1ccccc1)c1ccccc1 (D) CCC(C)C(C)Br",
            "options": [
                "(C)<(B)<(A)<(D)",
                "(D)<(A)<(B)<(C)",
                "(D)<(B)<(A)<(C)",
                "(C)<(D)<(B)<(A)"
            ],
            "answer": "(D)<(A)<(B)<(C)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 66,
            "question": "Match List - I with List - II. (A) Bronze (B) Brass (C) UK silver coin (D) Stainless steel. (I) Cu, Ni (II) Fe, Cr, Ni, C (III) Cu, Zn (IV) Cu, Sn",
            "options": [
                "(A)-(IV), (B)-(II), (C)-(III), (D)-(I)",
                "(A)-(IV), (B)-(III), (C)-(I), (D)-(II)",
                "(A)-(III), (B)-(IV), (C)-(II), (D)-(I)",
                "(A)-(III), (B)-(I), (C)-(IV), (D)-(II)"
            ],
            "answer": "(A)-(IV), (B)-(III), (C)-(I), (D)-(II)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 67,
            "question": "Match List - I with List - II. List - I: (Isomers of C₁₀H₁₄) (A) CC1CC2=C(CCC=C2)C1 (B) CC1=CC2=C(CCCC2)C1 (C) CC1C=CC2=C(CCC2)C1 (D) CC1=CCC2=C1CCCC2. List - II: (Ozonolysis product) (I) CC(C=O)CC(=O)NC(=O)C=O (II) CC(=O)C(=O)CC(=O)CC=O (III) CC(CC(=O)C=O)CC(=O)CCC=O (IV) CC(=O)CC(=O)OC(=O)C=O",
            "options": [
                "(A)-(I), (B)-(IV), (C)-(III), (D)-(II)",
                "(A)-(III), (B)-(II), (C)-(I), (D)-(IV)",
                "(A)-(III), (B)-(IV), (C)-(I), (D)-(II)",
                "(A)-(II), (B)-(III), (C)-(I), (D)-(IV)"
            ],
            "answer": "(A)-(III), (B)-(IV), (C)-(I), (D)-(II)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 68,
            "question": "pH of water is 7 at 25°C. If water is heated to 80°C, its pH will:",
            "options": [
                "Decrease",
                "H⁺ concentration increases, OH⁻ concentration decreases",
                "Remains the same",
                "Increase"
            ],
            "answer": "Decrease"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 69,
            "question": "Identify the coordination complexes in which the central metal ion has d⁴ configuration. (A) [FeO₄]²⁻ (B) [Mn(CN)₆]³⁻ (C) [Fe(CN)₆]³⁻ (D) CC(C)(C)OC(=O)CCO (E) [NiF₆]²⁻",
            "options": [
                "(B), (C) and (D) only",
                "(C) and (E) only",
                "(B) and (D) only",
                "(A), (B) and (E) only"
            ],
            "answer": "(B) and (D) only"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 70,
            "question": "When a non-volatile solute is added to the solvent, the vapour pressure of the solvent decreases by 10 mm of Hg. The mole fraction of the solute in the solution is 0.2. What would be the mole fraction of the solvent if decrease in vapour pressure is 20 mm of Hg?",
            "options": [
                "0.8",
                "0.4",
                "0.2",
                "0.6"
            ],
            "answer": "0.6"
        }
    ]
}